Get over it.
Over the Hedge is a family, comedy, animation
film directed by Karey Kirkpatrick.
A scheming raccoon fools a mismatched family of forest creatures into helping him repay a debt of food, by invading the
new suburban sprawl that popped up while they were hibernating – and learns a lesson about family himself.
RJ (voice), played by Bruce Willis.
Verne (voice), played by Garry Shandling.
Hammy (voice), played by Steve Carell.
Stella (voice), played by Wanda Sykes.
Ozzie (voice), played by William Shatner.
Vincent (voice), played by Nick Nolte.
Over the Hedge is a 2006 American animated heist comedy film directed by Tim Johnson and Karey Kirkpatrick and written by
Len Blum, Lorne Cameron, David Hoselton and Kirkpatrick, based on the comic strip by Michael Fry and T.
Produced by DreamWorks Animation, the film features the voices of Bruce Willis, Garry
Shandling, Steve Carell, William Shatner, Wanda Sykes and Nick Nolte.
Set in Indiana, the plot follows RJ, a raccoon who is forced to deliver food to a bear named Vincent after accidentally destroying his stockpile of food, whereupon
he manipulates a family of woodland animals who have recently awakened from hibernation into helping him steal food in order to speed up the process.
Over the Hedge was theatrically released in the United
States on May 19, 2006 by Paramount Pictures.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics and was a commercial
success, grossing $339.8 million worldwide on an $80 million budget.
The film explores themes of suburbian idyll,
garbage, entrapment, squirrel, garden.
The tone is lighthearted.